ARJUN **NAIR**

575 W Madison St, Chicago, IL · (669) 2419274 arjun.nair89@outlook.com· LinkedIn

A front-end enthusiast. My current profile is as of full-stack engineer, with React component rendering on the client with data provided with a Spring boot application. A feature rich application running on the latest trends of technology. Agility ensured with scrums, cards, CI, CD implementations. Learning opportunities which are self-challenging and motivators. I also am awarded with Google's scholarship partnered with Udacity for the Mobile Web Specialist Nanodegree program(Syllabus). And am stretching myself on the last phase of the course. As a part of the course I have been working on a project Restaurant reviews, which is available on GIT.

EXPERIENCE

MAY 2018 – PRESENT
FULL STACK DEVELOPER, KFORCE (CLIENT - EXPEDIA) TRAVEL AND HOSPITALITY CHICAGO, IL

- Created re-suable React component with limited props, with the help of Mobx viewstore and models.
- Handling the react state with Mobx, with the observe-observer pattern.
- Application perfroms array and object operations where large data sets are expected.
- Polyflills(Babel) are used support all the browsers while leveraging the ES6 features.
- CSS is compiled from less.
- CSS is coded ensuring interface is available on all browsers.
- Interfaces are developed with accessibility enabled, opening gates to larger crowd.
- Current project support Desktop, tablet and phone, flex boxes and other CSS techniques were used to support the responsive patterns.
- Use flow and eslint for ensure best practices are followed.
- Yarn is used and the build manager and serving the live application for development.
- Serviceworkers are used to enhance the offline capabilities of the app.
- Created a service in spring boot connecting to 3rd party end points.
- Generating PDF and CSV on fly.
- Use GIT for collaborating development effort. Create branches and PRs for different cards assigned
- Review PRs and address review comment ensuring the best version is merged.
- Demo the application enhancements and bugs fixed for every 2 weeks.
- Participate in analyzing and judging the efforts in sprint planning.
- Supporting production deployment on rotation basis.
- Be prompt on the feedback channel and be able to judge and fix P1 and P0 prod issues.
- Maintain feature flags ensuring lesser development effort and high application availability.
- Testing the applications against the requirements before each deployment to ensure stability and avoid regression.
- Understand the infra and check for the possibilities for improvements.

JUL 2017 – MAY 2018 FRONT END DEVELOPER, WIPRO (CLIENT - APPLE) MFG

SUNNYVALE, CA

- Project and Role: To build a tool for MPN/Go Live Matrix creation, and management process on a comprehensive database of marketing part numbers and facets (attributes), including LOB, project code, localization, capacity, color, and management process on a comprehensive database of marketing part numbers and facets (attributes), including LOB, project code, localization, capacity, color, country, channel, group (wave), status and date. I had been responsible creating wireframes for the Material Part Number Management and the localization screens. Design discussions on the UI front. Provide proper UX and calculate the time frame. Proper navigations from one screen to another based on conditions. Create a dynamic UI where user can interact and create materials through D3 provided Dendrogram. Use formatters and other advanced data binding techniques to achieve complex requirements. 11 components created for 11 different functional modules ranging from administration to submission of a document.
- https://github.com/a3qube/WAI Self-initiated project using Angular 4, What Am I. (Initial Stage).
- Prototyping user interfaces
- Provided Robust UI solutions
- Think of out of the box solutions to achieve various complex requirements.
- Mapping complex RESTful model to UI elements utilizing the \$expand and the \$select for optimization over the network calls. Thus, utilizing the framework standards.
- Minification of the UI5 application using GRUNT tool along with npm(NODEjs)
- Reduce and design rigid code base by understanding the requirements properly and thus reducing re-work.
- Use Angular JS for a custom application. We employed with the same MVC pattern as followed by SAPUI5
- Integrated Dendrogram a D3.js product.
- A dynamic Dendrogram supporting drag and drop and activation and deactivation node.
- Use the databinding feature of Angular JS to bind controls with the Model
- Custom directives to achieve various functionalities.
- Creating custom applications with HTML CSS and JS
- Use jQuery to ease development time and boost performance
- Use angular CLI, to create components and services.
- Angular 2 Typescript language to create components and mock data.
- Create wireframes with adobe photoshop CS6 and SAP Build tool.
- Create reusable code and make them generic as possible thus reducing development time.
- Maintain the standards of coding, provided by SAP UI5 and ECMA6. Which enables easy switch on version upgrades.
- Discuss with clients on the technical challenges and bring out designs that are reliable and robust
- Creating components and transport requests and managing their release.
- Our projects are offshore-onsite driven model. I was responsible in bridging the gap between and provide timely deliverables and updates on the progress on a regular basis.
- Handling 2 onsite resources and 3 offshore resources. Am responsible for tracking the
 progress, updating to the client, alert client well ahead about any foreseen exigency or
 deviation on the given schedule.

- Update team with the latest updates and help whenever there is a show stopper.
- Forecasting risk and planning for proper resolutions and backup plans.
- Conducting technical interviews for SAP UI5.
- Implementing the different JavaScript patterns and implement it
- Optimization of the applications by reducing the calls and engineering business functionalities on the backend.

JAN 2015 - AUG 2016

SAP UI5 / JAVA / HANA DEVELOPER, WIPRO (CLIENT – SAP LABS) PRODUCT

BANGALORE, KA, INDIA.

Project - eDaas - eDocument as a Service

- Involved in creation of the UI for these process tasks which would be handled by the users. Standard functionalities were used the most to adhere to SAP Standards.
- Was responsible to create 2 screens, for registration and for handling the process tasks.
- Create Java components to automate the business logic.
- Used SPRING framework(MVC), to create the java components.
- Hibernate and JPA, was used as the ORM for persisting and for the CURD operations.
- MAVEN was used as the build tool.
- APACHE olingo to create the RESTful WS(oData) and with integration in Spring beans.
- Use APIs provided by HANA to integrate into cloud.
- End Points communications are achieved by SAP HCI
- Developing FIORI applications for managing the process content.(Standard)
- Using design guidelines and take part in design thinking process.
- Prototyping with stencils and FIORI provided prototyping tools.
- Debugging the application with different mechanisms.

AUG 2016 – JUL 2017

SAP PORTAL LEAD, WIPRO (CLIENT - JNJ) - PHARMA

BANNGLAORE, KA, INDIA AND PISCATWAY, NJ

- Handling the SAP MDM materials module.
- Creating import and syndication maps for interfaces.
- Analyzing business requirements and suggesting the best possible methodology and the best practices.
- Handling the System administration, User Administration, PCD. Transports of WD components and the PCD contents.
- Creating transports and migrating during different testing and IT phase.
- Create CUT-OVER plan to ensure successful GO-LIVE.
- Creating jobs by with the help of provided SAP MDM APIs
- Create custom UI with Webdynpro Java for the MDM objects.
- Our projects are offshore-onsite driven model. I was responsible in bridging the gap between and provide timely deliverables and updates on the progress on a regular basis.
- Delegating responsibilities to offshore team and updating with the requirements and suggesting best practices.
- Review code and plan for healthy check-in strategies.
- Educating new comers with the process and the requirements.

APR 2013 - FEB 2014

SAP PORTAL DEVELOPER, WIPRO (CLIENT – BRITISH PERTROLEUM) ENERGY

BANGALORE, KA, INDIA & HYDERABAD, AP, INDIA

- Develop Webdynpro screens with JAVA APIS for SAP MDM.
- Working on the Portal v7.0 administration and user Management.
- Debugging various applications and WS.
- Deploying application and managing the PCD contents.
- Organizing and transporting the contents to different environments.
- Migrating code base upgradation from MDM API 7.0 to 7.1. Ensuring optimizations.
- Handling the SRM solutions having numerous system to bond with.
- Woking with the MDM DM, MDM Console, MDM Import Manager, MDM Syndication Manager.
- Working on Excel APIs for customized solution for SRM.

APR 2012 - FEB 2013

SAP PI DEVELOPER, WIPRO (CLIENT - BRITISH PERTROLEUM) ENERGY

BANGALORE, KA, INDIA

SAP PI – Intermediate interface developments.

JAN 2011 - FEB 2012

SAP PORTAL DEVELOPER, WIPRO (CLIENT – BRITISH PERTROLEUM) ENERGY

BANGALORE, KA, INDIA

- Develop UI screens.
- Basic component controller methods.
- MDM Java APIs
- Staging Area with Oracle SQL
- DTO objects to communicate to the staging area.
- SAP BPM Basics

EDUCATION

NOV 2014

MS SOFTWARE ENGG., BITS PILANI

- CGPA 7.0
- Work integrated course Wipro + BITS Pilani.

MARCH 2010

BACHELORS IN COMPUTER SCI., N.S.S. OTTAPALAM

- Percentile 81%
- National Cadet Corps Cadet and awarded B-Certificate
- National Service Scheme member
- President ROTRACT Club Ottapalam. 1Yr.

Attended the GNIIT course to keep up with the industry standards.

SKILLS

- JavaScript
- SAP UI5 / OPEN UI5
- Angular JS
- Bootstrap
- Chrome Debugging
- WEB IDE
- Java
- Agile Methodology with JIRA.
- Upgrades
 - Nodejs
 - o GIT
- SAP MDM
- SAP MDM Java APIs
- SAP EP Webdynpro Java
- Familiar with eclipse and enthusiastic to work on any IDE.

- Requirement Understanding
- Team coordination
- Provide feasibility analysis
- Understanding the environment and provide optimized solutions
- Handle offshore-onsite model
- Tackling tough situations.
- Update on the latest release in all the technologies involved.